Alexander Arizola

Full-stack Developer

Bothell, Washington United States

425-780-2304 alexarizola46@gmail.com

Authorized to work in the United States for any employer.

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I hold years of customer service, tech support and project management. I have experience with several programming languages and utilized them during my freelance development career. I am considered a good person to get along with and to work with and work best in teams, have a good sense of humor and have experience in leadership when it comes to software developing and group projects. In my freetime, I enjoy spending time with my family and listening to music.

SKILLS

I hold experience with issue tracking and task management. I've implemented task tracking processes using tools like trello and github issue tracking. Keeping track of issues and ensuring that the correct department or developer is assigned to the relevant issues.

As a developer, I have experience in several languages and tools. For database systems, I utilize the 3NF approach, indexes, capable of optimizing queries using DBA tools, and able to maintain database security through the use of permissions and access control (like IP whitelisting).

As I used PHP, I familiarized myself with object oriented programming, laravel framework, writing and using APIs and using the blade templating engine (laravel front end bits).

I speak, write and understand English expertly as my first language as well as being capable of understanding and speaking Spanish.

Development Languages & Tools

- Lua
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript / TypeScript / jQuery
- React / Material UI
- PHP / Laravel
- Source Control (Git / GitHub / GitLab)
- Project & Issue tracking (GitHub / GitLab / Trello)
- Dependency Managers (NPM)
- Database Systems (MySQL)
- Source Code Editors (Visual Studio Code / Atom)

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Development - Full-stack Developer

NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Developed software for various websites and gaming communities
- Created roadmaps with relevant timelines and release schedules
- Implemented issue tracking solutions and deployment processes
- Assisted consumers with inquiries
- Lead a development team through multiple projects, including delegating tasks, pair programming, and code reviews
- Familiarized myself with several programming languages, such as Lua, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, PHP

Amazon Locker (Redmond, WA) - FC Associate I, Direct

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Process packages into and out of the site
- Lift and move heavy payload
- Receive and put away inventory
- Troubleshoot problems
- Work under various types of customer volumes (fast-paced, slow)

EDUCATION

North Creek High School (North Creek, WA) - High School Diploma

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2021

Attended and studied for 4 years.

Lake Washington Institute of Technology (Kirkland, WA)

JANUARY 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

Attended and studied for a few months for college coursework.